Roxie Henderson papers, Inclusive: 1852-1919, undated, Bulk: 1914-1918, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Roxie Henderson papers
Inclusive: 1852-1919, undated, Bulk: 1914-1918, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
11
Henderson, Roxie, d. 1941
1 document box and 1 oversized box.
The Roxie Henderson papers contain personal items and collected materials of Roxie Henderson. Henderson was a Baylor University graduate who served during World War I as an American Red Cross nurse.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Roxie Henderson was from West, Texas, and attended Baylor University from 1917-1920. In 1920, she received her Bachelor's Degree from Baylor University in education. While at Baylor, Henderson was a very active member of the Baylor student community. She was a participating member and secretary of the Overseas Club for which she hosted numerous meetings and parties in her home.
Henderson also served overseas during World War I as a nurse in the American Expeditionary Forces and as a member of the American Red Cross. During World War I, the American Red Cross experienced phenomenal growth and helped staff hospitals, ambulance companies and provided national and international relief. Throughout the war, more than eighteen thousand Red Cross nurses served in the Army and Navy Nurse Corps.
The majority of Henderson's time overseas was spent in France. While abroad, Henderson stayed in contact with Baylor University through the university's publications, The Lariat and The Daily Lariat. In her column in the newspaper, she wrote on her experiences overseas, her travels, her time in the Officers' Club, her observations of the troops and her experiences while serving in hospitals. Overall, she spoke highly of her time overseas. Henderson also worked as a traveling representative in France for the vocational education department for disabled soldiers. She was one of twenty-five representatives in France.
Roxie Henderson passed away on 1941 August 8, and is buried in Vaughan Cemetery in Hill County, Texas.
Scope and Content
The Roxie Henderson papers begin in 1852 and end in 1919. The Collected Materials series is the largest in the collection.
Henderson was a collector of various items that ranged from autographs of historical figures, postcards dating to the World War I period, and letters with historical signatures. The collection has one letter from William Frederick "Buffalo Bill" Cody and another from Daniel Webster.
Arrangement
The Roxie Henderson papers were not organized prior to this finding aid. All of the items were compiled into one folder. There were two incomplete inventories. Currently, the Roxie Henderson Collection is arranged in two series: I. Personal and II. Collected Materials.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 11. Acquired 1940-11-19
Related Resources
Related references
A Brief History of the American Red Cross. "About Us." Accessed 2013 February 18.
American Treasures of the Library of Congress. "The American Red Cross." Accessed 2013 February 18.
"Armistice... Shows Baylor Part in World War; 24 Men Answered Final Call." The Daily Lariat. Baylor University, Waco TX. 1926 November 15. Vol. 29, No. 41. Accessed 2013 February 18.
"Ex-'19-ER Writes." The Lariat. Baylor University, Waco TX. 1919 May 29. Vol. XX, No. 33. Accessed 2013 February 18.
Find a Grave, Inc. "Roxie M. Henderson." Memorial #69728324. Databases. Accessed 2013 February 19.
Harrison, Katharine., Ed. "The Round-Up 1920." Baylor University, Waco TX. 1920. Accessed 2013 February 18.
"In the Service." The Lariat. Baylor University, Waco TX. 1919 January 16. Vol. XX, No. 14. Accessed 2013 February 18.
"Miss Henderson Entertains." The Lariat. Baylor University, Waco, TX. 1920 January 29. Vol. XXI, No.16. Accessed 2013 February 18.
"Musical Program For Men From Camp, Miss Martin has Program for Soldier in Education Building." The Lariat. Baylor University, Waco TX. 1918 March 14. Vol. XIX, No. 23. Accessed 2013 February 18.
"Overseas Club Entertainment." The Lariat. Baylor University, Waco TX. 1920 January 15. Vol. XXI, No. 14. Accessed 2013 February 19.
"The Baylor Bulletin: A Directory of Ex-Students of the College of Arts and Sciences of Baylor University." Baylor University, Waco Texas. 1920 August. Vol. XXII, No. 4. Accessed 2013 February 18.
"The Baylor Bulletin, Baylor University: The Catalog, 1920-1921, Announcements, 1921-1922." Baylor University Press, Baylor University, Waco TX. 1921 May. Vol XXIV, No. 3. Accessed 2013 February 18.
"Society." The Daily Lariat. Baylor University, Waco TX. 1931 September 30. Vol. 35, No.9. Accessed 2013 February 18.
"You Might Like to Know." The Lariat. Baylor University, Waco TX. 1918 November 14. Vol. XX, No. 7. Accessed 2013 February 18.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- History.; Baylor University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Baylor University -- History -- 20th century.; Baylor University -- History, Military.
Subjects
Postcards.; World War, 1914-1918 -- United States.; World War, 1914-1918.
Genres
Correspondence.; Pamphlets.; Periodicals.
- Personal, 1887-1888, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The Personal Series contains the personal items of Roxie Henderson. This includes her autograph book, her bible and a collection of historical signatures. The materials are in good condition.
  - Bible, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Autograph Book, 1887-1888 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Historical Signatures, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Collected Materials, 1852-1919, undated; 2
  The Collected Materials Series contains items collected by Roxie Henderson. These items include letters from William Frederick "Buffalo Bill" Cody and Daniel Webster, an American Red Cross pamphlet, World War I era postcards and editions of The Stars and Stripes and The New York Herald. The materials are in good condition.
  - Letters, 1852 and undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Postcards, 1914-1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Periodical, The Stars and Stripes, 1918 December 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Periodical, The New York Herald, 1918 December 14 and 1919 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Periodical, The Stars and Stripes, 1919 June 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Periodical, The New York Herald, 1919 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)